bayer.com 2019-04-03

# Privacy Statement - Bayer

This website (hereinafter the “ ** _Website_** “) is provided by Bayer AG (hereinafter “ ** _us_** ” or “ ** _we_** ”). For further information regarding the provider of the Website, please refer to our imprint.

  1. ## Handling of personal data

In the following we wish to provide you with information on how we handle your personal data when you use our Website. Unless otherwise indicated in the following chapters, the legal basis for the handling of your personal data results from the fact that such handling is required to make available the functionalities of the Website requested by you (Art. 6(1)(b) General Data Protection Regulation).

    1. ### Using our Website

      1. #### Accessing our Website

When you call up our Website, your browser will transfer certain data to our web server. This is done for technical reasons and required to make available to you the requested information. To facilitate your access to the Website, the following data are collected, briefly stored and used:

        * IP address
        * Date and time of access  

        * Time zone difference to Greenwich Mean Time (GMT)  

        * Content of request (specific site)  

        * Status of access/HTTP status code  

        * Transferred volume of data  

        * Website requesting access  

        * Browser, language settings, version of browser software operating system and surface  

Moreover, to protect our legitimate interests, we will store such data for a limited period of time in order to be able to initiate a tracking of personal data in the event of actual or attempted unauthorized access to our servers (Art. 6(1)(f) General Data Protection Regulation).

      2. #### Setting of cookies

        1. ##### What are cookies?

This Website uses so-called “cookies”. Cookies are small text files that are stored in the memory of your terminal via your browser. They store certain information (e.g. your preferred language or site settings) which your browser may (depending on the lifespan of the cookie) retransmit to us upon your next visit to our Website.

        2. ##### What cookies do we use?

We differentiate between two categories of cookies: (1) functional cookies, without which the functionality of our Website would be reduced, and (2) **optional cookies** used for website analysis and marketing purposes. The following tables contain a detailed description of the optional cookies we use: 

###### Optional Cookies 

Purpose and content| Lifespan| On/Off  
---|---|---  
Website analysis with Google Analytics:   
These cookies assign a randomly generated ID to your device, enabling us to recognize your device upon your next access. For details on website analysis please see the respective chapter below. | 6 months | 

Google Analytics OnOff  
  
Analysis of webcast with Multimedia Center from West:  
These Cookies enable us to analyze your use of the webcast by assigning a unique and randomly generated ID to your device that lets us recognize if you have used the Multimedia Center player once before. | 12 months | 

Webcast OnOff  
  
        3. ##### Subject to your consent

We only use optional cookies if we have obtained your prior consent (Art. 6(1)(a) General Data Protection Regulation). Upon your first access to our Website, a banner will appear, asking you to give us your consent to the setting of optional cookies. If your consent is given, we will place a cookie on your computer and the banner will not appear again as long as the cookie is active. After expiration of the cookie’s lifespan, or if you actively delete the cookie, the banner will reappear upon your next visit to our Website and again ask for your consent.

        4. ##### How to prevent the setting of cookies

Of course you may use our Website without any cookies being set. In your browser, you can at any time configure or completely deactivate the use of cookies. This may, however, lead to a restriction of the functions or have adverse effects on the user-friendliness of our Website. You may at any time object to the setting of optional cookies by using the respective objection option indicated in the table above.

      3. #### Website Analysis

**Google Analytics**  
On our Website we use Google Analytics, a web analysis service of Google Inc., 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, United States (“ **Google** ”).  
Google will analyze your use of our Website on our behalf. To this purpose we use, among others, the cookies described in more detail in the above table. The information collected by Google in connection with your use of our Website (e.g. the referring URL, our webpages visited by you, your browser type, your language settings, your operating system, your screen resolution) will be transmitted to a server of Google in the US, where it will be stored and analyzed. The respective results will then be made available to us in anonymized form. Your usage data will not be connected to your full IP address during this process. We have activated on our Website the IP anonymizing function offered by Google, which will delete the last 8 digits (type IPv4) or the last 80 bits (type IPv6) of your IP address. Moreover, Google is certified under the [EU-US Privacy Shield](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI), which ensures that an adequate level of data protection is maintained with respect to the processing of data by Google in the US.  
You may revoke your consent to the use of web analysis at any time, either by downloading and installing the [provided Google Browser Plugin](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en-GB) or by administrating your consents in the above table, in which case an opt-out cookie will be placed. Both options will prevent the application of web analysis only as long as you use the browser on which you installed the plugin and do not delete the opt-out cookie.  
Further information on Google Analytics is available in the [Google Analytics Terms of Use](https://www.google.com/analytics/terms/us.html), the [Privacy and Data Protection Guidelines of Google Analytics](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en-GB) and in the [Google Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy).

**Multimedia Center from West**  
On our website we use the external analytics service Multimedia Center of our webcast provider WEST UC Limited, a West LLC company, Unit 1 & 2 Sawmills End Barnwood, Gloucester GL4 3D, Great Britain („ **West** “).  
West will analyze your use of our webcast on our behalf.   
To this purpose we use, among others, the cookies described in more detail in the above table. The information collected by West in connection with your use of our webcast (e.g. the referring URL, our webpages visited by you, your browser type, your language settings, your operating system, your screen resolution, date, duration of your viewing, part of the webcast you viewed) will be transmitted to a server of Nasdaq in Germany, where it will be stored and analyzed. The respective results will then be made available to us in anonymized form. Your usage data will not be connected to your full IP address during this process.  
You may revoke your consent to the use of web analysis for webcasts at any time by administrating your consents in the above table, in which case an opt-out cookie will be placed.  
Further information on West is available in the [West privacy statement](https://www.west.com/legal-privacy/#digital-communications).

      4. #### Use of contact forms

You can contact us directly via the contact forms available on our Website. In particular, you may provide us with the following information:

        * Name, surname and title
        * Country
        * Contact data (e.g. e-mail address, phone number)
        * Message

We collect, process and use the information provided by you via the contact forms exclusively for the processing of your specific request. 

      5. #### Subscription to our newsletter

On our Website, you may subscribe to receive our newsletter. Based on your prior consent, we will collect and use the email address you indicate for providing you with the newsletter (Art. 6(1)(a) General Data Protection Regulation).  
If you wish to receive a customized newsletter, you may, on a voluntary basis, provide us with the following additional information: 

        * Name and surname
        * Title
        * Media, Department
        * City, Country
        * Language
        * Subject(s) of interest

For subscription to our newsletter we use the so-called double opt-in procedure. After you have subscribed to the newsletter on our Website, we will send you a message to the indicated email address asking for your confirmation. If you do not confirm your subscription, your subscription will automatically be deleted. In order to prevent any misuse of your personal data, we will log your subscription and confirmation, filing the IP address you use when subscribing, the time of your subscription and confirmation, the messages sent by us regarding your subscription, and the wording of your subscription and confirmation.   

You may at any time with future effect revoke your consent to receive our newsletter. To declare that you wish to unsubscribe, you may use the respective link included in all newsletters, or refer to the contacts indicated below.  

      6. #### External services or content on our Website

We include third-party services and/or content on our Website. When you use such third-party services or when third-party content is displayed, communication data are exchanged between you and the respective provider for technical reasons.   

The respective provider of the services or content may also process your data for own additional purposes. To the best of our knowledge, we have configured the services and content of providers known to process data for own purposes in such a way that either any communication for other purposes than to present their services or content on our Website is blocked, or communication only takes place once you have actively opted to use the respective service. However, since we have no control over data collected and processed by third parties, we are not in a position to provide binding information regarding the scope and purpose of such processing of your data.  

For further information regarding the scope and purpose of such collection and processing of your data, please consult the privacy statements of the providers whose services and/or content we include and who are responsible for the protection of your data in this context:  

        * TV-Footage
        * Stockholders’ Portal
      7. #### Registration for closed user groups

        1. Our TV-Footage material is only offered to journalists to support editorial coverage of Bayer. We check your access authorization and once your right of access has been verified, we will create an user account for you in which we will file the following personal data:

          * Name and surname 
          * Expert group, tv station/editorial department 
          * Contact data (incl. email address and phone number) 
          * Country and city 
          * User name and password 
        2. ##### Limited access for special user groups

There are further specific information that we can only share with a limited group of people. Therefore we file the following personal data:

          * Name and surname 
          * User name and password
          * E-mail address

We process this personal data in order to provide you with an access to our website. They are automatically deleted in case you deactivate your user account.

        3. ##### Stockholders‘ Portal

The stockholders‘ portal is only offered to stockholders of Bayer AG. The login for our stockholders’ service is handled by the service provider [Link Market Services GmbH](https://www.linkmarketservices.de/datenschutz.html). We process these personal data provided by Link Market Services in order to allow your access to our website. These data are automatically deleted at the fixed date November 30th after one year in case you deactivate your user account or sell your shares in Bayer AG.  
You will find your data for the first log-in to our Stockholders' Portal in the invitation to the Annual Stockholders' Meeting of Bayer AG.

      8. #### Information on side effects and quality complaints

This Website is not intended or designed for communications regarding side effects, lack of therapeutic effect, medication errors, grey market products/counterfeit medicine, incorrect or off-label use, quality complaints and/or other issues regarding the safeness or quality of Bayer products. If you wish to report side effects or make a quality complaint, please contact your health care professional (e.g. physician or pharmacist), your local health authority, or use our [Website for the report of undesirable side effects](http://www.bayer.com/pharmacovigilance).  

If you nevertheless report to us undesirable side effects or other issues regarding the safeness or quality of Bayer products, we will be legally bound to deal with your communication and may have to contact you for clarification purposes. Subsequently, we may have to notify the competent health authorities of the issues reported by you. In this context, your information will be forwarded in pseudonymized form, i.e. no information by which you may be directly identified will be passed on. We may also have to forward these pseudonymized notifications to our group companies and cooperation partners, to the extent these are likewise obliged to notify their respectively competent health authorities.   

Further information about data privacy and side effect reporting are available in the Bayer Privacy Statement for Pharmacovigilance Data.

      9. #### Use of Publication Order

On our Website, you may order/subscribe many of our publications. Based on your prior consent, we will collect and use the address details you indicate for providing you with the publication: 

        * Surname 
        * Address (Street, Post code, Town or City, State/Province, Country) 
        * E-mail adress
        * Phone number

You are welcome to provide us with the following optional information:

        * Title 
        * First name 
        * Company 
        * Department 
      10. #### User Surveys

Participation in the user surveys conducted from time to time on our website is voluntary. We use functional cookies to carry out the user surveys. The technical information recorded by the user survey is the same information that is recorded when users visit the website (see above). Your responses submitted during the user survey will not be linked to your personal data such as your IP address.

    2. ### Transfer of data for commissioned processing

For the processing of your data we will to some extent use specialized service contractors. Such service contractors are carefully selected and regularly monitored by us. Based on respective data processor agreements, they will only process personal data upon our instruction and strictly in accordance with our directives.  

    3. ### Processing of data outside the EU / the EEA

Your data will in part also be processed in countries outside the European Union (“ **EU** ”) or the European Economic Area (“ **EEA** ”), which may have a lower data protection level than European countries. In such cases, we will ensure that a sufficient level of protection is provided for your data, e.g. by concluding specific agreements with our contractual partners (copy available on request), or we will ask for your explicit consent to such processing.  

  2. ## Information regarding your rights

The following rights are in general available to you according to applicable data privacy laws:  

    * Right of information about your personal data stored by us; 
    * Right to request the correction, deletion or restricted processing of your personal data; 
    * Right to object to a processing for reasons of our own legitimate interest, public interest, or profiling, unless we are able to proof that compelling, warranted reasons superseding your interests, rights and freedom exist, or that such processing is done for purposes of the assertion, exercise or defense of legal claims;
    * Right to data portability; 
    * Right to file a complaint with a data protection authority; 
    * You may at any time with future effect revoke your consent to the collection, processing and use of your personal data. For further information please refer to the chapters above describing the processing of data based on your consent.

If you wish to exercise your rights, please address your request to the contact form or to our company data protection office indicated below.  

  3. ## Contact

For any questions you may have with respect to data privacy, please use the provided contact form or contact our company data protection officer at the following address: 

Group Data Protection Officer  
Bayer AG  
51368 Leverkusen  

  4. ## Amendment of Privacy Statement

We may update our Privacy Statement from time to time. Updates of our Privacy Statement will be published on our Website. Any amendments become effective upon publication on our Website. We therefore recommend that you regularly visit the site to keep yourself informed on possible updates.   

**Last updated: March 13, 2018**
